globalsight.com 2008-05-09

# Transware - Privacy Statement

This policy has been developed to comply with the Irish Data Protection Acts 1988 and 2003 and the European Communities (Electronic Communications Networks and Services) (Data Protection and Privacy) Regulations 2003. For information on Irish data protection legislation and the Data Protection Commissioner, please follow this link: [www.dataprivacy.ie](http://www.dataprivacy.ie./)

In general, Transware does not collect, store, use or disclose personal information except for information which you volunteer in certain circumstances, such as, for example, when you register with us to obtain access to certain know-how that we make available on our website.. Whenever we collect such information, you will have a choice regarding whether to provide it, how it will be used, and to whom it will be disclosed. The instances in which Transware does collect and use information are specifically described in this policy.

Transware provides certain services on its website, including information and support resources (the “Services”). The Services may also be located on third party Web sites and/or applications. The Services are made available by Transware plc and its subsidiaries and associated companies (collectively “Transware”). Transware values its users and takes seriously concerns about their privacy. To this end, Transware applies in consistent data processing practices and uses its best efforts to make clear disclosures regarding such practices.

## What does this policy cover?

This policy applies to collection, use, storage and disclosure of information by Transware. Where, in specific circumstances we depart from the terms of this policy, we will explain the nature of that departure and give you an opportunity to choose not to participate or provide the information. By using the Services and our website, you consent to the collection and use of your information as outlined in this policy.

Transware may decide to change this policy from time to time. When we do, we will make the amended policy available on our website. Please be aware that, as part of the Services, Transware provides links to websites operated by third parties. Transware is not responsible for content, the information collection or privacy practices of third party websites.

## What information does Transware collect? How is it used? Does Transware disclose information to third parties?

Transware may collect any or all of the following four types of information: (a) traffic or clickstream data, (b) cookies, (c) pixel tags or (d) contact information and other personal information. Transware's collection and use of each type of data is described below, as well as the ways (if any) in which the data may be shared with third parties. Please note that Transware may transfer any information in its possession to any third party in connection with a sale of all or a substantial part of the assets of the company, a sale of the company or a merger.

**(a) Traffic or Clickstream Data.** Anonymous/statistical data about traffic and usage which does not include personal information and is not supplemented or combined with personally identifying or identifiable information. Transware may freely share information it collects with third parties, but only in aggregated, anonymous form. Transware collects some information regarding use of the Services by observing browser functions and the files users access. For example, Transware's servers may collect anonymous information about the site from which you entered to counter fraud and to identify areas and issues of common interest to visitors to our website in order to improve the experience we offer. In addition to the foregoing applications, Transware uses the information (in aggregate form) to better design the Services.

**(b) Cookies.** Like many organisations, Transware collects information about online behaviour using cookies. These cookies contain identification information that enables us to see how our users are interacting with our site and how frequently they are returning, as well as to evaluate and improve their experience of our Services and to help diagnose problems with our servers. Our cookies do not contain any personally identifiable information. Cookies let us know about repeat visitors and the Services are useful and relevant.

Transware may also use cookies to identify which sites our repeat visitors are coming from so that we can provide the most relevant and useful information to users of our website.. To Transware, using information within cookies is an anonymous way to evaluate and improve our Services.

Finally, we may offer you the ability to have easier access to password-protected areas of our website by giving you the opportunity to access such areas automatically using a cookie which we would set on your computer.

You may set your browser software to reject cookies, but this may restrict your access to the Services. Transware may share information about usage of the Services with third parties, but only in aggregated, anonymous form.

**(c) Contact Information and other Personal Information.** Transware obtains access to your name, e-mail address and other contact information only (1) when you contact us, provide comments, submit a problem, or request information from Transware and provide your name and return contact information (including address, e-mail, telephone and/or fax numbers), (2) in connection with special offers, promotions or competitions, or (3) when you provide such personal information to access certain restricted areas of our website, to indicate your interest in partnering with Transware or to express your interest in sealing employment with Transware.

Transware may share information with companies who work on our behalf to provide certain services, such as email processing and delivery and conducting research and analysis. These companies will be prohibited from using this information for any other purpose or from sharing this information with other companies.

Transware may also use personal information held by it to respond to legal process, such as, search warrants and court orders, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims.

Contact information provided in connection with problems, comments or requests is used only to respond to those problems, comments or requests. Unless you expressly otherwise agree, this information is not used in connection with traffic or clickstream data and is provided to third parties only as necessary to respond to the comment, problem or request.

Finally, you may choose to provide contact information, other personal information, and demographic information in order to participate in optional surveys or contests, which are run for promotional purposes. Transware uses such information to send you information about its products in accordance with the terms and conditions attaching to such surveys or contests (to which you will be asked specifically to consent) and to notify you if you win the contest. When you give us your personal information, we will give you the opportunity to opt out of receiving information from us regarding Transware or Transware's business partners by post or telephone and either give you the opportunity to opt in to receive such information by electronic means (including e-mail, fax or SMS) or notify you that the provision of your personal information will be taken to constitute opting in to receiving such information by electronic means.

By returning or submitting a form with your personal information to us, you consent to (a) our processing your Sensitive Information for the above purposes (but see further below; and (b) our transferring your information to countries which may provide a lesser standard of data protection than either Ireland or your country of residence if necessary for the above purposes. If we do make such a transfer we will put a contract in place to ensure your personal information is protected.

**(d) CVs and resumes.** If you opt to apply for employment with Transware or to send us your CV or resume in connection with any such application or otherwise, we will forward such information to our HR Personnel who will hold and process the information on a strictly confidential basis. Please note, however, that the internet is not a secure communications medium and we accept no liability for any breach of confidentiality arising directly or indirectly from transmission of your personal information via the internet.

Where you send us information such as CVs or resumes, we hold such information on file for up to two years from the date of receipt by us. This is to allow us to maintain your details on file and to contact you in the event a job vacancy becomes available. You may, at any time, contact us to request the deletion from our files of your CV or resume. If we wish to retain your CV, resume or other similar document beyond the term of two years stated above (e.g. where we anticipate a suitable job vacancy arising within the two year period referred to above), we will contact you (as outlined below) to seek your consent to such retention.

It is your responsibility to ensure that the contact information outlined in your CV, resume or any associated correspondence is confidential and we reserve the right to contact you (generally and in connection with job applications you make to us) using any means of contact information which you furnish to us. Accordingly, we recommend that a private e-mail address is used when submitting CVs, resumes or other similar personal information.

## What information does Transware not collect?

We do not seek to or intentionally collect Sensitive Data. Our procedures and systems are not established or equipped to receive or handle appropriately Sensitive Data which you may send to us. We will never ask you for Sensitive Data in connection with the use of the Services. Accordingly, you agree and undertake not to provide Transware with Sensitive Data relating to you or to any other person and indemnify Transware against any liability arising from the provision by you of such Sensitive Data. For the purposes of this policy, Sensitive Data constitutes sensitive personal data as defined in the Irish Data Protection Acts 1998 and 2003 including (without limitation) personally identifiable information as to:

(a) racial or ethnic origin  
(b) political opinions  
(c) religious/philosophical beliefs  
(d) trade-union membership  
(e) physical or mental health  
(f) or sexual orientation or other matters  
(g) the commission or alleged commission of offences or information relating to proceedings relating to such offences

## Is personal information stored by Transware secure?

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data integrity, and ensure the appropriate use of personal information, Transware has put in place physical, electronic, and organisational procedures to safeguard and secure the information it collects online. We aim to ensure your data is always safe. However, security standards and protocols are constantly evolving and we make no warranty as to the particular efficacy of the security measures adopted by us. You should consider any communication that you transmit to Transware (such as data, questions, answers, comments or suggestions) as non-confidential, and agree that Transware will not be liable or responsible if information that belongs to you is intercepted or used by an unintended recipient. 

## Does Transware collect personal information from or about children?

Transware uses reasonable efforts not to collect, use or disclose individually identifiable information from children under the age of 18. The Services are not targeted at children, and children may not register for any portions of the Services that require registration.

## How can I access or correct any personally identifying information about me?

To request a copy of the personally information you have sent to Transware, please send an e-mail containing your request to [privacy@transware.com](mailto:privacy@transware.com). You must provide your full name and the e-mail from which the request is received (and to which the response will be sent) must match the e-mail on file with Transware. You may then correct or delete such information using the procedures specified in the e-mail. We may charge a small fee for access to your personal information in this way.

## Further Information

Where you contact us by telephone, please note that we may monitor or record telephone calls to make sure we follow your instructions correctly, to improve our service to you and to assist in training our staff. If you have any questions about this policy or any matter arising from it, or about Transware's collection and/or processing of personal information please contact Transware as follows:

Transware, Marketing Director  
Transware, 7901 Stoneridge Drive, Suite 500, Pleasanton, California USA  
Tel: +1 925 734-3000  
Fax: +1 925 224-8642  
E-Mail: [privacy@transware.com](mailto:privacy@transware.com)

You may also use the above contact information if you think any information held by Transware about you is inaccurate, incomplete if you want to change the sort of information about you that Transware may have collected or if you wish to opt out from receiving information from Transware in the future.

This policy was last revised on 20th Oct, 2004.
